Esraa Afifi

Product Designer (UI/UX)

Behance Profile

esraaafifi1996@gmail.com

+20 1128293864Live in **UAE**, **Egypt**

Languages

Arabic Native

English Advanced

Skills

Prototyping

UX Testing

Wireframing

Design System

User interviews

User Flow

User Research

Visual design

Tools

Figma

Miro

Adobe Xd

Jira

Sketch

Webflow

Zeplin

Education

Computer science Bachelor degree @Ain shams University

Computer system department Ain shams University

Graduation project Grade: Excellent

Understanding

HTML5

ReactJS

CSS4

Bootstrap5

JS

APIs , Ajax, Webpack

Summary

Product Designer (UI/UX) with +4 years experience ,leading design strategies, defining product specifications ,conducting user research validated UX success through testing and working with responsive web & mobile designs , as well as a problem solver with strong analytical skills , proven technical, organizational, and communication skills .

Computer science graduate with development, testing and management skills.

Experience

Naqla / Product Designer (UI/UX)

naqla

LinkedIn Profile

Nov 2022 - Present

- Revamped B2C & B2B Customer Application .
- Created a design system, wireframes and workflow for customer app .
- Collaborated with system analysis and participated in the development cycle .
- Negotiated with stakeholders and developers to find the balance between user needs and business objectives.
- Worked on Customer app create order & payment modules .
- Worked closely with sales and CRM teams to gather and analysis users data.
- Led team of junior designers in creating backend portal for internal employees.

Tagaddod / Product Designer (UI/UX)

TAGADDOD

Jan 2021 - Nov 2022 (Part-time Remotely)

- Worked on GreenPan customer <u>webforms</u> and authentication designs which increased the number of visitors by 20%.
- Designed GreenPan warehouse webform and ticketing system .
- Improved <u>Tagaddod webforms</u> designs & chat module ,increased users interaction by 23%, 5k+ daily unique visitors and 1k+ downloads on play store.
- Collaborated with the backend team to design admin panel portal .
- Revamped Customer/Collector/ Apps and webforms .

AKWAD / UI/UX Designer



Jan 2019 - Nov 2022 (Full-time Remotely)

- Re-Designed job and candidate details modules on <u>Techimatter Project</u>
- Designed offline mode & Grades system features in <u>Learnovia App</u>.
- Collaborated with developer team & managed a wide variety of crossmedia projects involving branding, UI designs, user research and led design strategy of 2 products (<u>Tajmeel</u> & <u>Tagaddod</u>).

PlateOne / Senior UI/UX Designer

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019 (Part time Remotely)

- Designed interactive <u>website</u> for governmental company based in Saudi Arabia.
- Worked with Figma & AdobeXD to create interactive modules (sign up, create profile, add companies).
- Designed <u>Job seeker profile</u> and <u>add new advertisement</u>.

Professional Skills

- Designing technical impactful products across multiple platforms including iOS, Android and Web
- Experience with web and admin interfaces (Tagaddod Project)
- Creating wireframes & mockups & Prototypes & usability testing and A/B tests.
- Manage project delivery Project planning and analysis.
- Advanced knowledge of Design Systems
- Knowledge of interaction design, user-centered design processes, as well as knowledge of UX principles and techniques.
- Review and iterate on current designs and participate in the product development life cycle.
- User Research ,UX Research (quantitative and qualitative) and UX Testing
- Strong communication skills and a good team player